{"tossups": [{"question": "This ruler won battles at the Hellespont and Chrysopolis to put down a revolt led by Licinius. At one battle, this man claimed he saw a Chi-Rho in the sky with the words \u201cin this sign, you will conquer.\u201dMaxentius was defeated by this man at the Battle of Milvian Bridge. The Edict of Milan, which granted tolerance to Christians, was issued by this emperor. For ten points, name this \u201cGreat\u201d Roman Emperor, the first to convert to Christianity.", "answer": "<b> Constantine</b> the Great (accept<b> Constantine</b> I)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This island\u2019s Deltaterrasserne [\u201cdelta\u201d-\u201dterra\u201d-sern] site was inhabited by the Independence I and II cultures. Archaeologists discovered the ruins of the Saqqaq culture around this island\u2019s Disko Bay. The northernmost point of this island is named after philanthropist Morris Jesup. The US Air Force maintains Thule Base on this island, where over 30% of the population lives in the capital, Nuuk. For ten points, name this largest island in the world, an autonomous country within Denmark.", "answer": "<b> Greenland</b> (or<b> Kalaallit Nunaat</b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "Golden examples of these objects are reflected on a black background in \u201cAftermath of Obliteration of Eternity,\u201d one of Yayoi Kusama\u2019s Infinity Mirror Rooms. Man Ray depicted five of these objects in a 1930 \u201cRayograph,\u201d which he created by using these objects and photosensitive paper. Near the center of Picasso\u2019s war protest painting<em> Guernica</em>, one of these objects explodes near the ceiling. For ten points, name these luminescent household objects developed by Thomas Edison.", "answer": "<b> light</b>bulbs (accept<b> bulb</b>s; accept<b> lamp</b>s)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This group killed thousands of people in the Sinjar Massacre, which targeted Yazidis in the region of Nineveh. On October 27, 2019, the leader of this group committed suicide after being cornered in the Idlib province of Syria; he was replaced by Abu Ibrahim al-Hashimi, whose precise identity is still unconfirmed. Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi led, for ten points, what Wahhabist terrorist group that, at its height in 2015, controlled parts of Syria and Iraq?", "answer": "<b> IS</b>IS (or<b> IS</b>IL; accept<b> Islamic State</b> of Iraq and Syria; accept<b> Islamic State</b> of Iraq and the Levant; accept<b> Daesh</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This object, which contains a decree from an assembly of priests in Canopus, was given the designation EA24 in the British Museum. Pierre-Francois Bouchard discovered this object at Fort Julien during a Napoleonic campaign. This object, the most visited item in the British Museum, was studied by Jean-Francois Champollion, whose work ushered in modern Egyptology. For ten points, name this slab of rock whose inscribed Greek and Demotic texts helped decipher Egyptian hieroglyphics.", "answer": "<b> Rosetta Stone</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In 1603, an ice floe destroyed this city\u2019s first permanent bridge, which connected it to the<em> jurydyka</em> of Praga. A shoemaker named Jan Kilinski led the armed peasantry of this city against the occupying Russian Empire in a 1794 uprising. J\u00a8urgen Stroop suppressed an uprising in this city, eventually sending most of the rebels to Treblinka and other death camps. A 1943 ghetto uprising took place in, for ten points, what capital city of Poland?", "answer": "<b> Warsaw</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "After winning this event in 1987, Harry Carson dumped a bucket of popcorn over President Reagan\u2019s head at the White House. CEO Jed York claimed to have \u201cpulled the plug\u201d on one of these events in 2013, refuting Ray Lewis\u2019 claim that the power outage at the Louisiana Superdome was a conspiracy. For ten points, name this event, annually the most-watched television program in the United States, that determines the champion of the NFL.", "answer": "<b> Super Bowl</b> (accept<b> Super Bowl</b> 21 and/or 47; prompt on descriptive answers of the NFL\u2019s championship game)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "After this ruler ignored a plea for peace, John Dickinson drafted a \u201cDeclaration of the Causes and Necessity of Taking Up Arms.\u201d This monarch appointed Lord Rockingham as Prime Minister in favor of Lord Grenville. The Olive Branch Petition was rejected by this ruler, who later was forced to accept peace with the United States after Lord Cornwallis\u2019s men surrendered at Yorktown. For ten points, name this British king during the American Revolution.", "answer": "<b> George III</b> (prompt on George) Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This city was briefly ruled by the Thirty Tyrants, a client government of their rival. Citizens of this city could vote to expel others by depositing pottery shards in urns, a process known as ostracism that was used against statesmen like Themistocles. During this city\u2019s Golden Age under Pericles, the Parthenon was built. For ten points, name this \u201cbirthplace of democracy,\u201d a powerful city-state of ancient Greece.", "answer": "<b> Athens</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "George Washington Cabell from Tennessee led a committee that decided to revise this act instead of preparing for war. The British violation of neutrality during the Chesapeake Affair encouraged Congress to pass this act, which was later expanded in the Non-Intercourse Act. This act was personified as a turtle in a political cartoon biting a man who says \u201cOh! This cursed Ograbme.\u201d For ten points, name this economically crippling 1807 act that banned all foreign ships from entering US ports.", "answer": "<b> Embargo</b> Act of 1807", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this English scientist whose work on determining the structure of DNA was co-opted by Watson and Crick.", "answer": "Rosalind Elsie<b> Franklin</b>", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "These people allegedly saluted Mount Kaimon and dropped flowers as they departed. An instruction manual designed for these people commanded them to shout \u201chissatsu\u201d in their final moments and look for a point of entry between a smoke stack and a bridge. The term \u201ctyphoon of steel\u201d was applied to the Battle of Okinawa due to the prevalence of Mitsubishi Zeros piloted by, for ten points, what Japanese pilots who carried out suicide attacks?", "answer": "<b> kamikaze</b> pilots (accept<b> Tokubetsu Kogekitai</b>; prompt on partial answers, like \u201cpilots\u201d or\u201cJapanese people\u201d before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was allegedly so impressed by ally Isaac Brock that he presented the general to his troops, saying \u201cthis is a man!\u201d The numbers of this man\u2019s armies swelled after the New Madrid Earthquake was interpreted as a sign to join him; those alliances disintegrated with his death at the Battle of the Thames. For ten points, name this brother of \u201cthe Prophet,\u201d a Shawnee chief who led a coalition of natives in support of England during the War of 1812.", "answer": "<b> Tecumseh</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Bertrand Goldberg designed a pair of skyscrapers in this city that feature 19 floors of spiral parking ramps and a small dock for riverboats, the Marina City apartment complex. This city\u2019s most upscale commercial district, the Magnificent Mile, is found in the (+) </b> <b>Water Tower District, named for a building that survived an 1871 disaster. This city\u2019s Millennium Park, which opened four years late, contains Anish Kapoor\u2019s (*) </b> <em>Cloud Gate</em>, a sculpture nicknamed \u201cthe Bean.\u201d For ten points, name this Midwestern city whose architecture was heavily redesigned after a \u201cGreat\u201d 1871 fire.", "answer": "<b> Chicago</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "<b>A member of this family exiled the Strozzi and launched a war against Lucca. Opponents of this family included Francesco Salviati, who orchestrated a plot to kill some of its members during high Mass in the (+) Pazzi conspiracy. The Albizzi attempted to curb the influence of this family by expelling one of their leading members, but that man, (*)</b> Cosimo, returned the next year. Pope Leo X was a member of this family, as was Lorenzo the Magnificent. Michelangelo was under the patronage of, for ten points, what family that ruled medieval Florence?", "answer": "<b> Medici</b> family", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A woman who married into this family had tomatoes thrown at her in Switzerland while on her \u201cRainbow Tour.\u201d Supporters of a leader from this family were killed in the Ezeiza</b> <b>Massacre. (+)</b> <b>Jorge Videla led a coup against a leader of the Justicialist party from this</b> <b>family, which was supported by the \u201cshirtless ones,\u201d the (*)</b> descamisados. After a champion of women\u2019s suffrage died of cancer in 1952, the patriarch of this family re-married Isabel in 1961. For ten points, name this surname shared by Evita and her husband, a 20th century Argentinian president named Juan.", "answer": "<b> Per\u00b4on</b> family (accept Eva \u201cEvita\u201d<b> Per\u00b4on</b>; accept Juan<b> Per\u00b4on</b>; accept Isabel<b> Per\u00b4on</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Denis Kearny threatened to manufacture balloons for dropping dynamite on one of these places. People who came to one of these places after a 1906 earthquake were called \u201cpaper</b> <b>sons.\u201d (+)</b> <b>In one of these places, Doyers Street became known as \u201cMurder Alley\u201d due to</b> <b>violence among Tong gangs. Immigrants settled in one of these places in San Francisco after the repeal of an 1882 (*) </b> Exclusion Act. Paifang gates and dragon decorations are common in, for ten points, what urban neighborhoods developed by immigrants from a certain Asian country?", "answer": "<b> Chinatown</b>s (accept<b> Tangrenjie</b>)  (1) <b>This country attempted to gain self-government with the April Laws, written</b> <b>by nationalist leader Lajos Kossuth [LIE-osh KO-shooth]. Louis II was king of this country when it lost the 1526 Battle of (+) Moh\u00b4acs [moh-hotch]. Bela Kun and Janos Kadar [yah-nosh kadar] led Communist governments in this country, whose first king was Saint Stephen of the Arpad Dynasty in the first century AD. In 1867, this country (*) </b> merged with its western neighbor in the Ausgleich. For ten points, name this country that once formed a dual monarchy with Austria. ANSWER:<b> Hungary</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}